Hello again. Welcome to this video,
你好 欢迎观看本视频
where I'm going to be talking about Inference and Validation,
我将讲解推断和验证
as well as showing you my solution for the Fashion-MNIST network.
并演示我的 Fashion-MNIST 网络解决方案
So, inference and validation are related terms.
推断和验证是两个相关术语
Inference is when you take your trained network,
推断是用训练过的网络
and then you use it to make predictions.
进行预测
This is borrowed from statistics;
它来源于统计学
inferential statistics, where you have your data and you make some predictions about it.
推断统计学是对数据进行一定的预测
However, these predictions can actually be too good,
但是这些预测的效果实际上可能太好
and that your network learns
你的网络对训练集
your training set too well and it can't generalize to data it hasn't seen before.
学习地太好 无法泛化到网络未见过的数据
This is called overfitting.
这叫做过拟合
So, to test for overfitting,
为了检验过拟合
we use what's called validation.
需要进行验证
Basically, validation is you run your network
验证主要是对网络未见过的测试集
on a test set that your network hasn't seen before.
运行网络
It hasn't been trained on it, it's just data that's held out from your training set.
网络没有进行过这个测试集的训练 这些数据是从训练集中扩展出来的
What this does is,
这样
you can see how well your network performs on a dataset that it hasn't seen before.
你会发现网络对它未见过的数据集运行良好
So, if you get a really low training loss,
因此 如果训练损失非常低
but at a higher validation loss,
但验证损失非常高
that basically means your network is overfitting.
这意味着网络过拟合
It's having a hard time actually predicting images from your validation set.
根据验证集预测图像 会非常难
So, to prevent overfitting,
因此 为了防止过拟合
we use regularization such as dropout.
我们进行正则化 例如 丢弃法
I'll show you how to do that in this notebook.
我将在这个 notebook 给你演示怎么做
To start off, I'm just going to import our packages,
首先 导入数据包
and then load our data.
然后加载数据
Now, I'll show you how I build my network for the Fashion-MNIST dataset.
现在 我将给你演示如何为 Fashion-MNIST 数据集建立网络
So, I actually did a little bit more complicated, and I haven't shown you yet.
实际上 我做的稍微复杂一点 不过这里还没有演示
So, hopefully this will be instructive.
希望对你有所启发
So, what I want to do is build my network,
我想建立网络
so I can pass in an arbitrary number of the hidden layers.
传入随机数量的隐藏层
I could set the number of units in each of those hidden layers.
设置每个隐藏层中的单元数量
So, what I did is,
我的做法是
I just created my network, like normal-.module.
建立网络 例如 nn.Module
So, then in the init function,
在 init 函数中
I wanted to be able to pass in the input size and the output size, the hidden layers.
我希望能传入输入大小 输出大小 隐藏层
I'm also going to be using dropout,
我将采用丢弃法
so I can set a drop probability here.
可以在这里设置丢弃概率
So, then I wanted to add an arbitrary number of hidden layers.
然后 添加随机数量的隐藏层
To do this, I used nn.ModuleList.
使用 nn.ModuleList 实现这一点
Basically, functions like NormalList,
一般来说 ModuleList 的功能就像一般的列表一样
you can append to it,
附加内容
you can index it and so on.
添加索引等
But basically, it just helps，helps Pytorch
但是它一般只能帮助内部 PyTorch
keep track of the architecture of your network and display it.
跟踪并显示网络架构
So, here I'm just going to create a list,
这里只创建一个列表
put in the linear operation for the first layer.
传入第一层的线性运算
So, input size, hidden layers.
输入大小 隐藏层
So, that's going to be like an input layer into the first of the hidden layers.
相当于第一个隐藏层的输入层
So now, I need to add layers to my hidden layer list.
现在需要在隐藏层列表中添加层
So, it'll be like nn.Linear,
例如 nn.Linear
but I need to have a way to put in h1 and h2,
但是需要找到传入 h1 和 h2 的方法
where h1 is the input to some layer,
h1 是某个层的输入
then the output of that layer.
h2 是该层的输出
So, our hidden layers input from here,
因此 从这里输入的隐藏层
looks something like this.
是这样的
or 200, 100, 50. Something like this.
或者 200 100 50 就像这样
So, the list of like we have three layers,
列表中有三个层
the first three hidden layers,
三个隐藏层
the first one is 200 units,
第一层是 200 个单元
the second one is 100 units,
第二层是 100 个单元
the third one has 50 units.
第三层是 50 个单元
So, then what I need to do is something that looks like self.Linear 200 to 100,
我要做的就是 self.Linear(200, 100)
self.Linear 100 to 50,
self.Linear(100, 50)
self.Linear 50 to output size.
self.Linear(50, output_size)
But I want to do this programmatically,
但是我想以编程的方式实现
I don't want to have to hard-coding these numbers,
不想将这些数字硬编码
because I want to get them from this hidden layers.
因为我想从这些隐藏层中获取这些数字
So, we can do it to get these pairs 200, 100, 100, and 50.
可以取这些数字对 200 100 100 50
What you have to do is zip hidden layers and then take
要做的就是 压缩隐藏层
a slice from the first element to the last,
取从第一个元素到最后一个元素的切片
and then hidden layers from the second element to the last.
然后是从第二个元素到最后一个元素的隐藏层
So, the first thing that is going to come out of here is 200 and 100.
解压后首先出现的是 200 和 100
So, the first element out of zip is going to be the first and then the second,
所以 解压后的第一个元素是
so it's 200 and 100.
200 和 100
Then the second element is going to come out are going to be 100 and 50.
解压后的第二个元素是 100 和 50
So, this will actually give us our hidden layer sizes as tuples.
所以 隐藏层实际是以元组为单位
So, now I could use self.hidden layers.extend.
现在可以使用 self.hidden_layers.extend
This is just a list.
这只是一个列表
So, we can use extend just like you would list,
可以扩展这个列表
and then we're going to add our linear operations.
添加线性运算
So, that'll set up our arbitrary number of hidden layers.
这样就设置了随机数量的隐藏层
Therefore, our output layer self.output we want another linear layer here,
我们想让输出层 self.output 成为另一个线性层
and then output size.
输出大小
So they're up all there. I also want to use dropout,
就是这样 我还想使用丢弃法
so I can add a dropout module here.
所以可以在这里添加一个丢弃模块
This is simply nn.Dropout.
nn.Dropout
Then you can set the probability for dropout.
然后设置丢弃的概率
You can either hard-code it but I'm going to put it as drop p,
可以硬编码 但我使用 drop_p
which is one of our keyword arguments for our network.
它是网络的一个关键字参数
So, there we've defined the architecture of the network.
我们已经定义了网络架构
Next up is our forward method.
接下来是前向传播遍历
So, we have our hidden layers in this list,
这个列表里有隐藏层
self dot hidden layers and so we can just loop through this.
self. x 可以通过它进行循环
So, for each in self.hidden layers,
for each in self.hidden_layers,
then for each of those hidden layers,
对每个隐藏层
we're going to pass in x.
传入 x
So, you pass in x, the tensor goes to the hidden layer,
传入 x 之后 张量到达隐藏层
goes through this relu activation function,
经过这个 ReLU 激活函数
and then we're going to put dropout on it after the action activation.
在激活操作之后 执行丢弃法
So, for each layer, and hidden layers,
for each in self.hidden_layer
we pass it through this corresponding linear function,
让 x 经过对应的线性函数
and then it goes through this relu activation function,
然后经过这个 ReLU 激活函数
and then through dropout and then finally the last one, self.output.
之后经过丢弃法 最后经过 self.output
So, here I'm going to return the log softmax x dim one.
现在返回 log_softmax(x, dim=one)
So, before I was returning the logits,
返回对数几率之前
but now I'm actually just returning log softmax.
但是现在实际返回的是 log_softmax
So, there's a nice criterion loss function that we can use the log softmax,
log_softmax 可以使用一个很好的条件损失函数
and remember I was talking about how with softmax,
记住 我说的是在高难度的计算中
you can end up with these floating point and accuracies in really difficult computations,
如何利用 softmax 获得这些浮点和准确度
because some of your numbers are very close to zero,
因为有些数字非常接近零
and some of them could be like really close to one.
有些非常接近一
But when you work in the log-space,
但是在对数空间内操作时
your numbers are much better behaved.
数字结果好得多
So, you're like negative four or something like that.
例如 负四等
So, the computation is just much easier in
所以 在 softmax 概率分布的对数空间里
the log-space of the softmax probability distribution.
计算容易得多
Then since with the log softmax,
因为有 log_softmax
if we want to get out the actual probability distribution from softmax,
如果想从 softmax 中获得实际概率分布
then you just take the exponential.
可以取指数
Right, and that is basically it for our network architecture.
好了 网络架构就是这样
So, now we need to create the network and define our criterion and optimizer.
现在 需要建立网络 定义条件和优化器
So, we'll just call model network 784,
调用 model = network(784
input as normal, we want 10 out as normal.
一般输入是 784 一般输出是10
I'm just going to use a hidden layer with 500 units.
使用一个具有 500 个单元的隐藏层
So, we can add more, so 200, 500,
可以添加更多 200 500
whatever we want there,
想添加多少都行
and set our drop probability to 0.5.
将丢弃概率设为 0.5
Now, we can create our criterion.
现在可以创建条件
So, like I was talking about before,
我之前讲过
we have the log softmax as the output of our forward pass.
log_softmax 是前向传播遍历的输出
So, we can use the NLLLoss with this.
所以这里可以使用 NLLLoss
If you read the documentation here,
阅读这个文件就会发现
so, it's the negative log likelihood loss,
这是负对数似然损失
and it's useful for classification,
对分类有用
and it's the input given through forward
通过正向调用获得的输入
call is expected to contain the log probabilities of each class,
应包含每个类的对数概率
which is what we have here.
就是这里写的内容
So, we have the log probabilities of each class.
所以 每个类都有对数概率
So, this is the loss function that we want to use.
这是我们需要使用的损失函数
So, the optimizer, we are going to use the Adam Optimizer.
优化器 我们将使用 Adam 优化器
So, Adam is a variation of stochastic gradient descent,
Adam 是随机梯度下降的一个变形
but it uses momentum to increase the training speed, Ir.00.
它通过动量增加训练速度 Ir=0.001
Set the learning rate to 0.001.
将学习率设为 0.001
Okay, so, now that is all set up,
现在已经全部设置好了
and now, we can start writing our training code like normal.
可以开始正常编写训练代码
So, train for two epochs,
训练两个周期
our steps with zero,
步骤为 0
set our running_loss zero here.
运行损失设为零
We're going to print our losses every 40 steps,
每 40 步打印一次损失
for e in range (epochs).
for e in range (epochs)
So, now that we have this drop out,
因为已经使用了丢弃法
so one thing to note is that when we're training,
需要注意的是 在训练时
we want drop out to be on.
我们希望启用丢弃法
So we want there to be some probability for drop out.
希望有一定的丢弃概率
But when we are evaluating,
但是 在评估时
when we're trying to do inference or validation,
尝试推断或验证时
we need the drop out to be off.
希望禁用丢弃法
Because remember that drop out is just randomly
因为丢弃是随机
shutting off some of the connections and like dropping out some of the units.
关闭某些连接 丢弃某些单元
So, what that means is that,
换句话说
drop out is on and you're trying to do inference,
在启用丢弃法的情况下 尝试执行推断时
your network is not going to be working at its full capacity.
网络无法全容量运行
So, you're not going to get a good measurement.
所以 测量效果不好
You're going to get good predictions.
预测效果也不好
So we want to be able to turn off drop out when we're doing inference.
所以希望能在执行推断时禁用丢弃法
We want to be able to turn it on when we're training.
训练时再启用
So, PyTorch provides this pretty simply,
PyTorch 非常简单地实现了这一点
if you do model.train,
执行 model.train 时
it turns on drop out,
启用丢弃法
turns on everything that should be on while you're training,
启用训练时需要的所有东西
and then if you actually want to turn out stuff off, you say model.eval.
要想禁用丢弃法 输入 model.eval
So, you're basically setting up your model
这样就将模型设置成
in evaluation mode for inference and validation.
推断和验证的评估模式
So, at the beginning of this loop, we want to start
我们想让这个循环
in train mode, so obviously, model.train.
从训练模式开始 输入 model.train
So just for the training pass,
训练时的完整遍历
you've seen all this before,
之前已经讲过
so it's not too interesting.
不是新概念
Okay, so now, we're at the part where we want to print out our training loss,
我们现在想打印训练损失
so print_every equals zero.
print_every == 0
So when we print out training loss,
打印训练损失时
we also want to print out our validation loss.
还想打印验证损失
So we want to actually run our network,
想运行网络
we want to run our test set through the network and
通过网络运行测试集
test how well it's doing on data as we've seen before.
并测试它对之前所见数据的效果如何
So, we're doing inference here,
现在进行推断
so we want to make sure our model is in evaluation mode.
为了确保模型处于评估模式
This is going to shut off dropout.
丢弃法会被禁用
We want to know the accuracy and we also want to know the test_loss.
我们想知道准确度和测试损失
So, accuracy is just what's the probability
准确度就是
that our network actually predicts correctly what the image is.
网络正确预测图像内容的概率
So, we're going to loop through the images and labels in our test set,
我们将循环测试集中的图像和标签
so it's a test loader.
它是一个测试加载器
Normal, image.resize.
图像缩放
We're going to get our images and labels into variables.
获得的图像和标签是变量
So here, what we want to do with our variable,
对于变量
we actually want to set volatile equals true.
设置 volatile=True
So basically, what this means is we don't actually want to do back propagation,
意思就是 不想进行反向传播
we don't want to do a backward pass.
不想进行反向传播遍历
So, what this does is it shuts off autograd
这样的话 如果不关注运算过程
from actually keeping track of all operations if you don't really care about that.
就可以让 autograd 不再跟踪所有运算
So you want to do this when you're doing inference and
在进行推断和使用 PyTorch 模型时
with PyTorch models because like that takes a computation,
会这样设置 因为跟踪运算需要进行计算
it takes time, so it's just going to be faster if you just don't
需要花费时间 所以 如果不保留这些梯度
keep those gradients and we don't keep track of the operations that are happening.
不跟踪当前进行的运算 速度就会加快
So, when your inference mode,
所以 在推断模式下
you want to create your variables with volatile equals true.
创建易失性为真的变量
Then we will do a forward pass with our images and get our test_loss.
然后对图像进行前向传播遍历 获得 test_loss
Now, we want to calculate the accuracy.
现在计算准确度
To calculate our accuracy, we need to get our predictions first.
要计算准确度 首先需要获得预测值
So we'll get our probabilities from torch.exp.
根据 torch.exp 获得概率
So it's taking the exponential because remember that our output is the logs softmax.
它会取指数 因为输出是 log_softmax
So if we take the exponential of that,
如果取其指数
we'll just get back our softmax probability distribution over our classes.
会获得各个类之间的 softmax 概率分布
So, this gets us our probabilities and then we can test for equality.
获得概率 然后可以测试等同性
So we want to know our labels.
我们想测试标签
So labels is our true labels, right?
标签是真标签 对吧
So, are these equal to the labels that are predicted by our network?
这些标签是否等于网络预测的标签？
So, remember that ps here is our probability distribution and so we're taking the max.
记住 这里的 ps 是概率分布 取最大值
So basically, you're finding the class that has the highest probability.
所以一般会找到概率最大的类
So, what one here does is it gives us back
给我们返回
the index of the class with the highest probability.
概率最大的类的索引
So that way, we are testing the true labels with the predicted labels.
这样对真标签和预测标签进行测试
Because remember, this is predicting the index with the highest probability.
因为它预测的是概率最大的索引
So that's the when our network is saying like season nine and saying like that's a nine.
例如 网络提示“第九季”和提示“这是九”
So, this will basically give us true or false based on
根据实际真标签与网络预测标签是否相同
if the actual real labels are the same as the labels that were predicted by our network.
给我们返回“真”或者“假”
Then, we can calculate our accuracy and equality.
然后可以计算准确度 等同性
So remember, accuracy is basically
记住 准确度是
just how many predictions
网络所做的正确预测的次数
that our network get right divided by the total number of predictions it made.
除以它所做的预测总次数
So, since these are true and false,
由于值是真和假
they actually convert to ones and zeros.
实际可以转换成一和零
So true is one, false is zero,
真为一 假为零
so if you take the mean,
如果取均值
it actually gets converted to a sum of
会转换成正确预测总次数
all the correct ones divided by the total number of predictions you have.
除以预测总次数
So if you just take equality.mean,
如果取 equality.mean
then you will get back the accuracy of your network.
会获得网络的准确度
So, if you actually just try to run the code like this, you'll find that it breaks,
如果尝试以这种方式运行代码 你会发现它会中断
and basically, what happens is equality, I think,
等同性
it's like a Boolean type,
类似于布尔数据类型
like a Boolean tensor instead of a float tensor,
类似布尔张量 而不是浮动张量
but when you say.mean,
但是 如果输入 .mean
it needs to be a float tensor.
应该是浮动张量
So you actually have to convert it here.
所以这里需要转换
So say, type as torch.FloatTensor.
输入 type_as(torch.FloatTensor)
So basically, we're taking equality which we get from here,
从这里获得等同性
it's like a Boolean tensor,
它类似于布尔张量
we are converting it into
将其转换成
a float tensor and then taking the mean and that gives us our accuracy.
浮动张量 取均值 就会获得准确度
So this whole loop here is basically our validation loop.
整个循环就是验证循环
So we're going through all the images in the test loader and
对测试加载器中的所有图像进行这种操作
we are calculating the loss and we're calculating the accuracy.
计算损失 计算准确度
So, this will tell us how well our network is performing on data as it has seen.
这样就可以知道 网络对它见过的数据的效果如何
Okay, and then, just paste this in here.
将其粘贴在这里
So basically, this is just like printing out what epoch we're on,
打印当前周期
what's our training loss,
训练损失
what's our test loss,
测试损失
and what's our test accuracy.
以及测试准确度
So here, the test loader gets us the number of batches.
测试加载器给出了批数
So basically, the number of times you looped through here, right?
也就是循环的次数 对吧？
So then, we have our accuracy,
获得了准确度
we're just adding it all up, and we're just taking the mean.
将其相加 取均值
So we're just dividing by the total number of loops here and here.
除以循环总次数
So this is the average of our accuracy and the average of our test_loss.
就是准确度平均值和测试损失平均值
Finally, we need to set our running_loss back to zero at the end of here.
最后 需要将运行损失设为零
We also want to set the model back to training.
我们还想将模型设为训练模式
Now that we have it all written up,
代码已编写完毕
we can train our network.
可以训练网络了
So now, after training for two epochs,
训练两个周期之后
got our test accuracy up to about 0.85. So, it's pretty good.
获得的测试准确度约为 0.85 非常好
Now, we can just add our network and make sure it actually works.
现在可以添加网络 确保它能正常运行
So, I'm not exactly sure seven is the shoe but it thinks that seven is the shoe.
我不确定七是鞋子 但它认为七就是鞋子
So in the next part,
在下一部分
I'm going to show you how to save your trained models.
我将演示如何保存已训练模型
So, it doesn't really make a lot of sense to
每次需要时都训练一个新网络
train a new network every time you need it, so typically,
这样做的意义不大
what you'll do is train your network and then save it and then when you
所以应该训练并保存网络
need to do inference or maybe train it some more with new data,
在需要进行推断或用新数据训练时
you'll load it back up and then keep training
重新加载 持续训练
or use it for inference. See you next video.
或用它进行推断 下一段视频见